Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.3 Single Lectures and Addresses by Dr. Adler (500)
    - 507 Social Ethics
      - Moral Dangers of Life in a Great City, 1896 November 15 (Box 64, Folder 24)
      - The Perils of New York and the Moral Evils That Are Its Cause (Box 64, Folder 25)
      - Materialism of Great Cities and Its Effect on the Higher Ideals of Life, 1902 October 26 (Box 64, Folder 25a)
      - The Degradation of Great Cities and Its Remedies (Box 64, Folder 25b)
      - The Redemption of Great Cities (Box 64, Folder 25c)
      - Luxury in so far as it Affects the Condition of the Masses, [1893 October] (Box 65, Folder 26)
      - The Metropolitan Greatness of New York and the Vast Moral Problems It Raises, 1899 April 23 (Box 65, Folder 27)
      - Humanity Uprooted and Humanity Regenerated (Easter), 1930 April 20 (Box 65, Folder 28)
      - The Ethics of Luxury, 1878 January 5 (Box 65, Folder 28a)
      - Social Changes and Social Conservatism, 1878 December 29 (Box 65, Folder 29)
      - The Ethics of Property, 1879 March 9 (Box 65, Folder 30)
      - Is There A Danger of Conflict Between Classes?, 1886 October 31 (Box 65, Folder 31)
      - Child Labor and Education, 1887 January 23 (Box 65, Folder 32)
      - Child Labor in New York, 1887 January 16 (Box 65, Folder 33)
      - The Evil of Chi1d Labor: A Crime Against Humanity, 1902 March 16 (Box 65, Folder 34)
      - The Application of Ethical Principles to the Life in Cities, 1903 October 7 (Box 65, Folder 35)
      - Obstacles to Reform Movements in the City of New York (Box 65, Folder 36)
      - Obstacles to Friendliness Between the Different Races, 1910 November 6 (Box 65, Folder 37)
      - The Negro Problem in the United States, 1904 January 10 (Box 65, Folder 38)
      - Lights and Shadows in the Character of Reformers, 1916 January 9 (Box 65, Folder 39)
      - False Ethics in the Social Reform Movements of the Day, 1913 October 18 (Box 65, Folder 40)
      - A Way to Industrial Peace, 1919 November 9 (Box 65, Folder 41)
      - The Dark Side of American Life As Exemplified by Child Labor, 1910 January 16 (Box 65, Folder 42)
      - An Ethical Code for Men in Business, 1920 May 14-16 (Box 65, Folder 43)
      - The Ethical Principle in Industrial Relations, 1919 November 16 (Box 65, Folder 44)
      - The Dangers to Children in a Democratic Environment, 1916 January 23 (Box 65, Folder 45)
      - The Progressive Emancipation of Our City (What We Want New York to Be), [1909] October 31 (Box 65, Folder 46)
      - The Conception of Social Welfare, 1913 April 19 (Box 65, Folder 47)
      - The Ethical Motive in Business, 1919 January 12 (Box 65, Folder 48)
      - The Distinction Between Good and Bad Wealth, or Is the Ethical Attitude Possible in Business?, 1907 October 27 (Box 65, Folder 48a)
      - Business and Morality, 1907 June (Box 65, Folder 48b)
      - Can the Ethical Principle Really Penetrate the Bus. Wor1d?, 1923 January 21 (Box 65, Folder 48c)
      - New View of Childhood (Box 66, Folder 49)
      - The Outlook on the Future of the Human Peace from the Ethical Point of View, 1916 November 16 (Box 66, Folder 50)
      - The Highest Hopes for Humanity, 1901 January 6 (Box 66, Folder 50a)
      - What A Man Can Get Out of His Work (Cornell U.), 1917 May 1 (Box 66, Folder 51)
      - The Vision of New York As the Ideal Metropolis of the Future, 1917 January 12 (Box 66, Folder 52)
      - World Citizenship Opportunities and Obligations of the Schoo1 and Home, 1924 October 20 (Box 66, Folder 53)
      - The Outlook for Social Harmony, 1918 January 13 (Box 66, Folder 54)
      - The Spiritual View of Social Reform, 1913 December 7 and 1914 January 4 (Box 66, Folder 55)
      - Class War and Class Cooperation for Social Progress, 1920 November 15 (Box 66, Folder 56)
      - Shall Teachers Affiliate With Labor Unions, 1919 November 23 (Box 66, Folder 57)
      - A Statement of Principles Applicable to the Labor Movement, 1922 January 15 (Box 66, Folder 58)
      - The Change of Attitude Toward the Criminal, 1915 November 21 (Box 66, Folder 59)
      - Suggestions Toward An Ethical Program for the Labor Movement (Box 66, Folder 59a)
      - The Shifting of the Moral Standard in the Relation of Men and Women, 1914 January 18 (Box 66, Folder 60)
      - Our Attitude Toward the Undeveloped, 1906 January 28 (Box 66, Folder 61)
      - The Duty of Society to the Child in the Light of the Supreme Moral Rule, 1906 December 2 (Box 66, Folder 62)
      - The Moral Causes of the Recent Financial Stress, 1907 December 8 (Box 66, Folder 63)
    - 508 Politics
      - The Political Aspirations of Women, 1897 January 24 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - A Critique of Socialism from the Ethical Point of View, 1895 January 20 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - The First Fruits of Imperialism, 1899 March 12 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - The Ideal of Nationality (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - New Ideals of Democracy, 1912 January 21 (Box 66, Folder 4a)
      - A Protest Against the Russian Treaty (Imperfect), 1893 March 26 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Shall Russian Refugees Be Extradited As Assassins? (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - The Duty of Civilized Nations to the Uncivilized (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - The Causes of Anarchy and Its Remedies (Box 66, Folder 7a)
      - Treaty with Spain (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Moral Issues in the Election, [1928] (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Anarchy, 1886 May 9 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Anarchism and Its Methods, [1886] (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - The Great Issue in the Approaching Election, 1897 October 24 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Conscience in Politics, 1894 November 4 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - The Experiment of Popular Government in the United States, 1892 November 6 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - The Opening of New Horizons on the Future of Mankind, 1924 April 20 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - The Perpetuation of Patriotism After the War, 1917 November 4 (Box 67, Folder 16)
      - 100th Anniversary of the Signing of the Constitution, [1889] (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - The Need of New Political Leaders, 1896 (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - Political Regeneration of Cities, 1903 October 15 (Box 67, Folder 19)
      - Municipal Politics, [1888 ?] (Box 67, Folder 20)
      - The Purification of Municipal Politics, 1886 October 24 (Box 67, Folder 21)
      - The Political Situation in New York, 1893 November 5 (Box 67, Folder 22)
      - The Larger Issues of Municipal Reform, [1890 October 26] (Box 67, Folder 22a)
      - The Political Situation in, 1896 October 25 (Box 67, Folder 22b)
      - The Ethics of Party Loyalty, [1887 November 7] (Box 67, Folder 23)
      - On the Eve of the Decision on What New York Has at Stake, 1901 November 3 (Box 67, Folder 23a)
      - The Permanence of Political Reform, 1903 October 25 (Box 67, Folder 24)
      - Conscience in Politics, [1878 November 3] (Box 67, Folder 25)
      - The Peril of the Political Reform Movement in New York, 1895 October 20 (Box 67, Folder 26)
      - The Immorality of Nations, 1914 October 25 (Box 67, Folder 27)
      - Anarchical Tendencies in American Life, 1911 December 17 (Box 67, Folder 27a)
      - The Future of Civilization, 1914 November 29 (Box 67, Folder 28)
      - What Shall We Think of Socialism?, 1907 January 20 (Box 67, Folder 29)
      - Christianity and Socialism, 1910 November 20 (Box 67, Folder 29a)
      - Social Reform Versus Socialism (Box 67, Folder 29b)
      - Socialism and Ethics, 1895 January 27 (Box 67, Folder 29c)
      - The Perplexity of the Conscientious Voter in the Presidential Election, 1920 October 31 (Box 67, Folder 30)
      - Why Reform Movements in American Cities Have Failed, 1921 October 30 (Box 67, Folder 31)
      - A League of Nations on Ethical Principles, 1919 November 2 (Box 67, Folder 32)
      - The Moral Prerequisites of a League of Nations, 1918 November 17 (Box 67, Folder 32a)
      - Moral Questions Involved in the Proposed League of Nations, 1919 October 26 (Box 67, Folder 32b)
      - What Should Be Our Attitude Toward Bolshevik Russia?, 1902 November 7 (Box 67, Folder 33)
      - New Moral Forces in American Politics, 1912 October 30 and November 3 (Box 67, Folder 34)
      - The Political Situation in the United States (Box 67, Folder 34a)
      - Moral Issues in American Politics, [1885 ?] (Box 67, Folder 35)
      - The Proposal That An Intellectual Aristocracy Shall Rule the American People, 1922 December 17 (Box 67, Folder 36)
      - Organized Democracy (Cleveland), 1916 November 30 (Box 67, Folder 37)
      - Child Labor Amendment (New Orleans) (Box 67, Folder 38)
      - The Principles Which Should Guide the Citizen in Making His Choice for President, 1916 October 29 (Box 67, Folder 39)
      - New Moral Forces in American Politics, 1912 October 10 (Box 67, Folder 40)
      - Anti-Democratic Tendencies in American Life, 1903 January 18 (Box 67, Folder 41)
      - The Ethical Meaning of Loyalty, 1917 November 18 (Box 67, Folder 42)
      - The Loyalty of the Foreign Born Citizen to the American Ideal, 1915 October 31 (Box 68, Folder 42a)
      - The Coming' Contest and the Final Emancipation of New York, 1909 October 31 (Box 68, Folder 43)
      - Our Ideal of American Democracy and the Actual Conditions in American Politics and Business, 1910 January 30 (Box 68, Folder 44)
      - The Spiritual Basis of Reconstruction, 1919 January 5 (Box 68, Folder 45)
      - The Great Problem of Americanization, 1919 January 19 (Box 68, Folder 46)
      - Far-Reaching Changes in Our System of Government, 1920 January 25 (Box 68, Folder 47)
      - Our National Shortcomings; Our National Greatness, 1908 January 19 and 26 (Box 68, Folder 48)
      - (The Right Relation Between Church am State Under the American System of Government) Church and state in America, 1907 December 15 (Box 68, Folder 49)
      - Science of Nations Series (Notes), 1916 February 11 (Box 68, Folder 50)
      - Criticism of American Democracy, [1910 ?] September 25 (Box 68, Folder 51)
      - The Influence of Asiatic Dominion on the Future of the Republic (Box 68, Folder 52)
      - The Groping of the American People Toward More Vital Political Issues, 1922 November 5 (Box 68, Folder 53)
    - 509 Ethics and Morality
      - The Happiness Theory, 1885 November 8 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Is It True That Goodness Is Its Own Reward and A Bad Life Its Own Punishment?, [1893 March 5] (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - The Freedom of the Will, [1881] (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Peace (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - The Highest Good, 1880 May 2 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - The Old and the New, 1977 May 6 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - The Good Principle in Things, [188?] (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - The Reconciliation Between Man and Man and Between Man and Destiny, 1897 May 9 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - The Need of A New Statement of Ethical Truth, [1893 December 17?] (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Ideals and Dreams, 1877 March 25 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Some Fundamental Questions of Morality, 1883 March (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - The Essentials of the Spiritual Life, 1904 November 20 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - The Crowning Grace of the Moral Life, 1902 December 7 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - The Basic Principles of Ethics, 1898 November 27 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - Spiritual Unity, 1898 December 4 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - The Cornerstone of Morality, [1890 ?] (Box 68, Folder 16)
      - The Influence of Mind on Morality, 1887 May 8 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - The Principles of Morality Unchanging in All the Ages (Box 68, Folder 18)
      - The Ethical Principle of Self Control, 1900 November 11 (Box 68, Folder 18a)
      - The Happiness Theory, 1885 November 8 (Box 68, Folder 19)
      - The Ethics of Suicide, 1900 February 4 (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - From the Modern Point of View, Is the Voluntary Ending of One's 1ife Even Permissible?, 1923 January 7 (Box 68, Folder 20a)
      - Reasons for Right Conduct, 1899 December 3 (Box 68, Folder 20b)
      - Freedom of the Will, 1886 January 10 (Box 69, Folder 21)
      - The Necessity of Association, [circa 1890] (Box 69, Folder 22)
      - The Form of the New Ideal, 1877 April 3 (Box 69, Folder 22a)
      - Is Life Worth Living?, [circa 1890] (Box 69, Folder 23)
      - The Emancipating Influence of the Love of Truth, 1898 January 23 (Box 69, Folder 24)
      - Lessons from Nature, 1883 April 29 (Box 69, Folder 25)
      - Providence, [circa 1889] (Box 69, Folder 26)
      - The Meaning of Culture, 1887 February 20 (Box 69, Folder 27)
      - Spiritual Attitude toward Oppressors, 1904 December 4 (Box 69, Folder 27a)
      - The Search for What Is Eternal (The Quest for the Eternal), 1901 October 20 (Box 69, Folder 28)
      - The Power That Saves Men (Box 69, Folder 29)
      - Larger Claims and Nearer Duties, 1895 February 10 (Box 69, Folder 30)
      - Science and Ethics, 1894 April 22 (Box 69, Folder 31)
      - More Light, 1899 May 7 (Box 69, Folder 32)
      - The Ethics of Gratitude, [1880 ?] (Box 69, Folder 33)
      - The Reconciliation of Man with Han and Man with Fate, 1899 May 9 (Box 69, Folder 34)
      - The Spiritual Attitude Toward Our Neighbors, 1904 November 27 (Box 69, Folder 35)
      - The Spiritual Attitude Toward Men and Women, 1916 November 12 (Box 69, Folder 35a)
      - The Conflict of Duties, 1900 March 11 (Box 69, Folder 36)
      - Two Souls in the Breast of Man, 1904 December 11 (Box 69, Folder 37)
      - The Social Ideal, [1881] (Box 69, Folder 38)
      - Materialism, 1885 November 1 (Box 69, Folder 39)
      - Emerson's Doctrine of Friendship and of Compensation, 1903 November 1 (Box 69, Folder 40)
      - Spiritual Compensation, 1917 January 28 (Box 69, Folder 40a)
      - The Sublime Inspiration of the Ideal of Service, 1921 November 27 and December 4 (Box 69, Folder 41)
      - The Seven Ages of Men and Their Ethical Significance, 1921 May 13 (Box 69, Folder 42)
      - The Need of Supreme Ethical Rule in View of the Perplexities of Our Time; The Supreme Moral Rule, 1911 November 5, 11 (Box 69, Folder 43)
      - A New Rule of Ethical Living, 1925 November 22 (Box 69, Folder 43a)
      - Spiritual Self-Education, 1923 December 16 (Box 69, Folder 44)
      - Standards of Success in American Life, 1911 November 12 (Box 69, Folder 45)
      - The Punishment of Individuals and of Peoples, 1918 November 10 (Box 69, Folder 46)
      - Faith Provocative of Strife (Box 69, Folder 47)
      - The Problem of Personality, 1915 January 3 (Box 69, Folder 48)
      - The Reality of the Spiritual (St. Huberts), 1926 August 8 (Box 69, Folder 49)
      - The Problem of Moral Suffering, 1911 December 3 (Box 70, Folder 50)
      - The Head of Medusa or The Attitude Toward Suffering, 1902 November 16 (Box 70, Folder 50a)
      - Spiritual Love (St. Hubert 's), 1930 August 24 (Box 70, Folder 51)
      - The Secret of Spiritual Power, 1930 November 16 (Box 70, Folder 52)
      - The Great Duties of Life, 1879 January 12, 19 (Box 70, Folder 53)
      - To See Another Spirituality is to See Him in His Relations As Determined by the Spiritual Rule (Box 70, Folder 54)
      - First Lecture on Culture (Box 70, Folder 55)
      - Culture Compatible with Democracy? (Box 70, Folder 55a)
      - Personality: How to Develop It in the Family, the School, and Society (Int. Congress on Education, [1929] (Box 70, Folder 56)
        (printed copy: in English, French and Italian)
      - Critique of Monotheistic Religion (Box 70, Folder 57)
      - “Love Your Enemies” (St. Hubert’s), 1929 September 1 (Box 70, Folder 58)
      - The Need of Ethical Self-Management, 1917 January 21 (Box 70, Folder 59)
      - Self-Discipline (St. Huberts), 1923 August 5 (Box 70, Folder 59a)
      - The Spiritual Outlook on Life and Futurity, 1913 November 30 (Box 70, Folder 60)
      - The Ethical Principle in Social Reform, 1910 November 27 (Box 70, Folder 61)
      - The Spiritual Meaning of Love, 1916 December 10 (Box 70, Folder 62)
      - Life's Illusions, 1915 January 10 (Box 70, Folder 63)
      - The Source of Spiritual Power (London); Christian Ethics(St. Hubert’s), 1925 June 28 and August 16 (Box 70, Folder 64)
      - The Restless World Craving for Inner Peace, 1924 January 11 (Box 70, Folder 65)
      - The Democratic Attitude as an Element in the New Way of Living, 1902 November 23 (Box 70, Folder 66)
      - The Value of Courage as an Aid to the Spiritual Life, 1898 January 16 (Box 70, Folder 67)
      - Courage to Face Life Anew, 1920 January 4 (Box 70, Folder 67a)
      - How to Keep at the Level of One's Best Moments, 1916 January 16 (Box 70, Folder 68)
      - How to Reach the Better Nature in Others, 1915 December 5 (Box 70, Folder 69)
      - The Burden of Life and Man' s Spiritual Liberation, 1927 November 20 (Box 70, Folder 70)
      - The Road to Spiritual Freedom, 1928 December 8 (Box 70, Folder 70a)
      - The Struggle Between the Better and the Worse Nature in Human Beings, 1921 January 9 (Box 70, Folder 71)
        (Incomplete)
      - The Cardinal Principles of the Ethical Life, 1900 November 4 (Box 70, Folder 72)
      - "A New Commandment I Give Unto You", 1900 November 11 (Box 70, Folder 72a)
      - The Keynote of the Ethical Life (St. Louis, New York), 1907 October 13 and 20 (Box 70, Folder 73)
      - 37th Anniversary – the Meaning of Life, 1913 May 11 (Box 70, Folder 74)
      - The Ethical Problem (Philadelphia Philosophical Society) Presidential Address, 1928 December 29 (Box 70, Folder 75)
      - Moral Poison in Modern Literature, 1926 January 10 (Box 70, Folder 76)
      - The Greatest Thing in Life, 1900 April 1 (Box 70, Folder 77)
      - The Relation of Ethics to Social Science, [circa 1898] (Box 70, Folder 78)
      - The Doctrine of Human Inequality in Modern Philosophy, As A Sign of the Times, 1900 October 28 (Box 70, Folder 79)
      - Helps and Hindrances to the Spiritual Life (St. Hubert's), 1923 August 5 (Box 71, Folder 80)
      - The Ethical Attitude Toward Self-Expression and Self Sacrifice, 1925 December 6 (Box 71, Folder 81)
      - The Ethical Prerequisites of Personal Peace, 1917 December 16 (Box 71, Folder 82)
      - The Passionate Longing for a Better World, 1924 November 4 (Box 71, Folder 83)
      - [Striving after perfection] (St. Hubert's), 1932 August 21 (Box 71, Folder 84)
    - 510 Women
      - A New Sisterhood (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Women's Influence, 1894 April 1 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Woman (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Woman's Position in the Present, 1882 February 24 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Woman's Work in the Ethical Society, [1892-1893] (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Woman's Advancement (Box 71, Folder 6)
      - The True Mission of Woman, 1891 April 5 (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - The Political Aspirations of Women, 1897 January 24 (Box 71, Folder 8)
      - The Place of Woman in Religion, 1897 January 31 (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - The New Place of Women in Modern Society, 1897 January 10 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - The New Place of Woman in the Modern World, 1924 January 13 (Box 71, Folder 10a)
      - Woman's Mission, 1878 April 28 (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - Woman's Place in Industry, in the state, and in Science, 1891 April 12 (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - Position of Women in the Household, 1882 December 3 (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - The Education of Women to Freedom, 1877 April 22 (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - Position of Women, 1882 February 12 (Box 71, Folder 15)
      - The New Opportunity of Women in Citizenship, 1918 January 6 (Box 71, Folder 16)
      - Independence of the Modern Woman, 1913 January 12 (Box 71, Folder 17)
      - The Distinctive Part That Woman Is to Play (Smith College Address), 1927 January 20 (Box 71, Folder 18)
      - The Woman Suffrage Question, from the Ethical Point of View, 1909 November 7 (Box 71, Folder 19)
      - The Franchise for Women, [circa 1909] (Box 71, Folder 19a)
      - The Special Part of Woman in Promoting Moral and Religious Progress, 1911 November 19 (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - 511 God
      - Changes in the Conception of God, 1901 November 10, 17, and December 1 (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Do Men Desire Immortality?, 1902 March 30 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - The Name of God, 1897 November 7 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Belief in Immortality, 1886 December 12 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - (Box 71, Folder 4a)
      - The Belief in the Immortality of the Soul, 1907 November 10 (Box 71, Folder 4b)
      - Immortality: Part V. Paradise and Hell, 1876 November 19 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Reward and Punishment As Affecting; the Doctrine of Immortality, 1876 October 29 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Substitutes for the Idea of A Personal God, 1886 December 19 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Immortality--The Answer of the Modern Scientist to the Questions: Whence and Whither? (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Do Men Desire Immortality?, 1902 March 30 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - The Attitude of the Modern Mind Toward the Belief in God (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - The Belief in God; My Attitude Toward the Idea of God, 1909 November 21, 28 (Box 72, Folder 10a)
      - The Personal God, 1886 December 1 and 1901 April 7 (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - Immortality, 1876 November 12 and 1911 April 12 (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - The Idea of Immortality, 1909 December 5 (Box 72, Folder 12a)
      - Immortality, 1921 December 18 (Box 72, Folder 12b)
      - The Idea of God in the Life of Modern Man, 1912 November 24 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - Ethical Religion and the Idea of God, 1921 November 13 (Box 72, Folder 14)
      - The Ethical Interpretation of the Idea of God, 1911 January 15 (Box 72, Folder 14a)
      - The Belief in God from an Ethical Point of View (Box 72, Folder 14b)
      - The Ethical Interpretation of the Idea of Immortality, 1911 January 22 (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - The Idea of Immortality from the Ethical Point of View, 1909 December 5 (Box 72, Folder 15a)
      - The Social Conception of God (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Life, Death, and Eternity, 1915 December 12, 18 (Box 72, Folder 17)
      - Death and Immortality, 1921 December 11, 18 (Box 72, Folder 17a)
      - The Love of a God and of the Divine in Man, 1926 January 17 (Box 72, Folder 18)
      - The God in Man, 1913 November 23 (Box 72, Folder 19)
      - The Name of God, 1897 November 7 (Box 72, Folder 20)
      - The God in Man, 1913 November 23 (Box 72, Folder 21)
      - The Supreme Object of Religious Veneration, 1926 November 7 (Box 72, Folder 22)
      - The Service Rendered by Belief in A Personal God, [circa 1881 September ] (Box 72, Folder 23)
      - The Good God, 1881 March 20 (Box 72, Folder 24)
      - The Personality of God, [1881] (Box 72, Folder 25)
      - For the Sake of God, [circa 1880] (Box 72, Folder 26)
      - God, 1926 November 7 and 1931 August 30 (Box 72, Folder 27)
    - 512 Education
      - Children of Liberals (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Religion in the Public Schools, 1880 November 23 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - The Duty of Liberals in Regard to the Religious Education of Their Children, 1902 March 2 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Education and Liberty (pts. I pt. II, 512-29), 1878 March 17 and April 7 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Considerations of Duty Which Should Guide Parents in Selecting A School for Their Children (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - The Moral Instruction of the Young (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - The Enlightenment of the Masses, 1876 November 28 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - The Intellectual Future of the West, 1885 December 20 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Parent and Child, 1882 November 26 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - The Parental Relation as a Means of Educating the Parent (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Intellectual Culture of Mothers (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - Denominational Schools vs. Public Schools, [circa 1880] (Box 73, Folder 12)